Guide to the Aurelio Bulosan Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Aurelio Bulosan papers
1949-1979
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
2329
Bulosan, Aurelio
0.21 cubic feet 1 box
Papers of the brother of Filipino-American author, poet, and migrant laborer Carlos Bulosan
Aurelio Bulosan was the elder brother of Carlos Bulosan, a Filipino-American author, poet, and migrant laborer who left the Philippines for Seattle in 1930.
Arranged in 4 accessions:
Accession No. 2329-001, Aurelio Bulosan papers, 1949-1974
Accession No. 2329-002, Aurelio Bulosan collected papers by and about Carlos Bulosan, 1953-1956
Accession No. 2329-003, Aurelio Bulosan collected papers by and about Carlos Bulosan, 1952-1961
Accession No. 2329-004, Aurelio Bulosan correspondence, 1979
The collection contains correspondence and writings of Aurelio Bulosan regarding his brother, Carlos; correspondence, prose, and a play written by Carlos Bulosan; and clippings, memorials, and other materials about Carlos Bulosan.
Selections from the collection have been digitized and are available on the Libraries Digital Collections website.
The papers are open to all users.
Carlos Bulosan papers. Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries, Seattle, Washington.
Bulosan, Aurelio$vArchives; Bulosan, Carlos; Bulosan, Carlos; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Filipino American authors$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$y20th century; Poets, American$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$y20th century; Filipino Americans$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Filipino Americans$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; American literature$xFilipino American authors; American poetry$xFilipino American authors; Filipino American theater; Dramatists, American$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$y20th century; correspondence; writings; reminiscences; plays; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Arts and humanities; Immigrant, ethnic, and racial groups; Civil rights; Civil Rights; Literature; Seattle
- Aurelio Bulosan papers, 1949-1974; 2329-001; 0.21 cubic feet 1 box
  Contains incoming correspondence from Carlos Bulosan to his brother Aurelio Bulosan, reminiscence by Aurelio about Carlos, and general corresponce of Aurelio Bulosan.
  5 folders of personal papers.
  The papers are open to all users.
  View selections from this accession in digital format
  Donor: Aurelio Bulosan, November 1973.
  - Incoming letters
    - Carlos Bulosan, 1949-1955; 15 items (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Carlos Bulosan, 1953, undated; 2 items (Box-folder 1/2)
  - General correspondence, 1953, 1957-1974; 11 items (Box-folder 1/3-4)
  - Reminiscence about Carlos Bulosan, undated; 2 items (Box-folder 1/5)
- Aurelio Bulosan collected papers by and about Carlos Bulosan, 1953-1956; 2329-002; 7 folders
  Contains a play and prose by Carlos Bulosan as well as correspondence, memorials, and clippings collected by Aurelio Bulosan about his brother Carlos.
  Donor: Aurelio Bulosan, September 10, 1974.
  - Outgoing letters - Aurea (daughter of Aurelio Bulosan), 1953-1954; 2 items (Box-folder 1/6)
  - General correspondence, 1949, 1954-1956; 9 items (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Writings of Carlos Bulosan
    - Play - The General of the Philippines, undated; 1 item (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Prose, 5 items
      - "The Angel of My Father", undated (Box-folder 1/9)
      - "Be American", undated (Box-folder 1/9)
      - "Even the Rain Remembers", undated (Box-folder 1/9)
      - "Return of the Amorous Ghost", undated (Box-folder 1/9)
      - "Will You Mend My Broken Dreams, Mollier", undated (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Clipping of "Carlos Bulosan: the Politics of Literature," St. Louis Quarterly, v. 6, no. 2, undated (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Miscellany: memorials to Carlos Bulosan and clipping, undated; 3 items (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Clippings and letter, undated; 3 items (Box-folder 1/12)
- Aurelio Bulosan collected papers by and about Carlos Bulosan, 1952-1961; 2329-003; 1 folder
  Photocopies of letter from Carlos Bulosan, 1952, and clippings, 1961. Also includes reviews of Carlos Bulosan's "Sounds of Falling Light" and "Letters in Exile" and a letter from a prospective Yugoslav publisher (Milos Prakus).
  Donor:: Aurelio Bulosan, April 27, 1982.
- Aurelio Bulosan correspondence, 1979; 2329-004; 1 folder
  An exchange of a single letter each between Aurelio Bulosan and Mary Hatten
  Donor: Mary Hatten, August 19, 2011